Introduction

Faizan Atiq is a UX & UI designer with collective experience of over seven years in both digital design & development. I am designing cutting edge interface and empathy based user solutions.

Extensive portfolio of over 20 diversified projects in E-commerce, Food & Health, help for cause, corporate websites, HRMS, project management systems, environmental cause and large screen interactive demos Experiences.

He has been crafting solutions as a Web developer and designer at United Technical Services since 2012 in UAE. Faizan holds a Master's degree in Computer Science that specialises in the field of Software Engineering and has published a research paper titled "Modern Web Design using Adaptive Content Delivery Networks."







UX / UI

Web Design

App Design







Digital Design

Art Direction

Branding

Contact

mfaizanattique@gmail.com https://www.mfaizanatiq.com https://www.behance.net/mfaizanatiq

Work Experience

Web Developer & Graphics Designer

United Technical Services (UTS) Jan 2012 – Present Musaffah, Abu Dhabi UAE

Technical Assistant/Data Entry Operator

Embassy of Pakistan, Abu Dhabi, UAE Jul 2011 – Jan 2012 United Arab Emirates

Software Engineer

Medical Transcription Billing Company (Pvt) LTD Aug 2010 – Apr 2011 Rawalpindi, Pakistan

Education

Masters of Science (M.S) in Computer Science

SZABIST, Dubai | www.szabist.ac.ae 2014 - 2016

Bachelors of Information Technology

Barani Institue Of Information Technology, Pakistan | http://biit.edu.pk 2006 - 2010

Awards & Certifications

Gold Medal

MS in Computer Science | Sept 2017

Certificate of Appreciation

Dubai Muncipality | April 2016

Gamification

University of Pennsylvania on Coursera | March 2015

Tool Set & Expertise















Projects - Some of my interesting work

Name: UTS Store, CMS

Role: UX & UI Designer, Front end Developer

Area: Design, Web, Mobile App

UTS Store is an e-commerce platform built entirely by the in-house development team. The project focuses on selling the company's products and services to there existing customers.

This project is an augmentation of the existing purchasing process. Each process has been carefully studied and researched to build a seamless experience for both the Company's users, and it's customers.

The client required a seamless experience across all platforms, i.e. web and mobile phones.

The app design and every module are crafted to ensure seamless customer experience. e.g. the user can start the purchase on one platform and then move to another platform to complete the purchase. The project was designed and developed using the following tools and technologies like Adobe XD, Microsoft Visio, Adobe Photoshop, .net

Link: https://store.uts.ae

Name: Growserry Mobile App

Role: UX & UI Designer, Brand Consultant

Area: Design, Mobile App

The client required a solution that allowed it's users to search for ingredients and later get healthy recipes. The scope of work included corporate branding, mobile app design, website design, social media content designs, and periodic video content publications.

Links:

www.growserry.com instagram.com/growserry2017

Name: Muslim Aid Australia Mobile App

Role: UX & UI Designer, Front end Developer

Area: IOS App, Android App

The scope of the project was to design and develop a mobile app (ios and android) that could allow it's users to view organisations projects and then provide donations.

The answer was a mobile app built on the foundation of Google's material design. App follows the company's branding guidelines, iconography and graphic elements (colours & typography). The tools used are Adobe XD for wireframing & prototyping and Ionic framework for development.

Link: http://bit.ly/2Lk1JfQ

Name: Wasel Order App Culture & App Icon

Role: Designer Area: Branding

Wasel Order app icon focuses on the core business values, i.e. faster community-based delivery. The colour & culture conceptualises and highlights the importance of premium service to deliver everyday goods.

Link: http://bit.ly/2HdN3MP

Name: Media Table Demo

Role: UX & UI Designer, Developer

Area: Unity 3d

It's an interactive educational demo developed on Unity3d that explains the company's principals via intuitive presentation for windows. The most exciting part how each principal like oil drilling, water purification, logistics and other area works, later converting them into an interactive digital interface. The Project is by far my most exciting project. Link: http://bit.ly/2Jr4RsW